Congratulations.
>> Sorry about the weather.
>> No, that's that's fine. I mean, I spent
I spent some time this year and this is
very
>> familiar with this, but
>> just, you know, very blessed and
thankful to even have an opportunity to
play some more football, you know, at a,
you know, another prestigious
organization. and they all give the
[__]
>> What was appealing to you about being
here? What stand out most?
>> Um, just the just the structure from the
top down. I It was a great opportunity I
felt like I couldn't pass on. And, you
know, I know I'm going to be around a
great group of guys, going to be around
a great young quarterback and Drake, you
know, great coaching staff and coach
Rabel and Josh and, you know, even just
some uh defensive stand like I I know
I'm going to come across some like some
great people and I just look forward to
it. So
>> Romeo, we understand there was some
other teams involved and and kind of
making the bidding for you. What tilted
it in the Patriots fate?
Uh again, just piggybacking off of what
I said before, I just, you know, felt
like it was an opportunity I felt like I
could pass on in terms of just
continuously staying grounded and
growing on and off the field. I really
believe this is the place where I can
fulfill that at and
um yeah I'm just you know it's a lot of
things to process right now but long
story short I'm very grateful and I'm
very thankful to be exactly right
>> you mentioned the young quarterback like
Drake um what kind of impressed you
about him la uh specifically last year
and just what made you know getting to
play with him so
Um,
I mean just his
obviously his growth as a player on and
off the field that's really big. And I
think just
just being able to
lead the team cuz ultimately this game
is
team based there is since and this is
nothing against straight but again like
I said football is a team game where
each player each individual has a role
to fulfill
and I believe that I have their team in
both
what sort of role did they pitch to you
you played a lot outside last year. You
played a lot as the ex receiver. What
What did What do they told you they want
you to do here?
>> Um they haven't told me anything. I'm
not I wouldn't expect to obviously have
a specific role other than just wherever
I am on the field. That can be a return
of this area. attacking these in heavy
personnel where I got to block the
defender or
gaining
whatever amount of cactuses that there
is where I can just do my 111 and just
be the best player I can be for everyone
else before.
>> You do you have the ability with the
numbers to get where does that come? Is
that 10 me? Is that hard work? Where
does that hurt you?
>> Um just being wellrounded like I've
always been. Um,
and again that's just that's just how
this game is played. I mean there's
always
a great thing to have with strength and
to polarize in that would be good.
Ultimately if I had to
moralize it all this game is built up
knowing uh being the best player that
you can be and being the best human that
you can be off the field. Normal, how do
you describe yourself as a player and
what do you think your best qualities
are though on a field?
>> Um, I wouldn't really
excuse. Uh, like I said, I just feel I
can,
you know,
do everything really well. I mean, I can
as a well loss. I can catch the ball. I
can block on the perimeter.
And um
you know I've participated in teams over
my years in Green Bay and just outside
of that you know there's many other
areas that I can improve in and I look
forward to establish.
>> What do you want Patriots fans to know
about you?
>> That I'm very that I'm very lay low. I
don't you know but I I don't really do
much. Um, and
I'm no I'm no different than us in terms
of getting that me. So,
>> Romeo, how big of a factor was Mike
Brael in your decision to come to
Europe?
>> Um, it was real big, you know, cuz I I
mean, I've done
again, I know exactly who he is and I
know at some point where I am at this
point in my life, he was all for that
person. And I think that just speaks
volumes for itself. And you know,
outside of him to
our strength staff to our offensive
coordinator, our defensive coordinator,
from our owner, I just think everything
all around. It's just a great
opportunity to build up.
>> How nice is it to come to a warmer
climate?
>> Um, I mean, it feels it feels really
solid, but yeah. That's just
I mean weather shouldn't dictate
obviously what I do on the football
field. But long story short, it does
feel a little better.
>> Have you had a chance of possibly
getting alternatives in this offense?
>> Um I'll be really honest with you. I
would love to stay true to just
understanding where I am and coming into
a new system under our office and
coordinator. And yeah, I wouldn't really
specify that I'm going to go in with
this amount of targets and that amount
of targets because I've come from a
place, you know, that didn't really mean
much. And I give credit, you know,
obviously to Brian welcoming me with
open arms and Green Bay just
just based off their history and the
situation that we were in. So
>> what is the Patriots release Stefon
Davis that they obviously decided to
invest in you thoughts about just
stepping up the filling some cheese?
Um, I mean, I I understand it'll be big,
but just the I wouldn't really emphasize
just
clearly the role that I I would assume
from the outside real that everyone is
seeing. I think my mindset going into
this is just being the best player that
I can be, being the best teammate that I
can be, which I know I'm Gary capability
of doing, and just obviously building
the trust and their team from the c
commodery around being nurse forward.
So,
>> how much do you know about the other
receivers that you're joining? And in
fact, have you had a chance to talk to
any of them since Simon?
>> I I have not had the opportunity to
speak with any of them, and I look
forward to meeting them real soon.
uh
they've Josh has spoken the roof through
about about them and what they do and
you know I know I know a little bit of
Kyle I mean cuz he's from Los Angeles
>> where I was born and raised and I know
there's many more in that room that I
look forward to beating. I know Mac is
one of a kind. I saw it all across the
world. What is it?
>> What is it about working with Josh
McDaniels and being in this offense that
excites you, especially after being in
the same kind of West Coast system?
>> Um,
that's that's a great question. It's
just
>> I'm just grateful, bro.
>> Excuse me. Have you had a chance to talk
to Drake?
>> Yes, I have. I spoke with Drake. He is
an amazing person to be around. I love
his personality and
I just love who he was as a person.
>> You guys have a chance to talk about
maybe getting, you know, a lot of wide
receivers and quarterbacks have been and
it's early, but in the offseason get
together and do some throwing.
>> Uh yeah. Yeah, we have. And you know, I
look forward to that real soul. Um but
again, man, Drake's a great guy, amazing
quarterback, amazing person, and I'm
glad I get to be around. talking to Ben
Frael, Josh Drake seemed like this was a
perfect fit for you. They smiling about
it and everybody else having opportunity
to work with. How much do you think this
is the perfect fit for you in your
career?
>> I think it's really good for my career,
you know, uh just from the the sequence
of events that has went on within the
last
who knows what it could be, week, month,
x amount of years. Um
again.
>> I'm very grateful. I'm very thankful to
be exactly where.
>> Do you smile once? You quiet? You seem
like you're quiet.
>> Yes.
>> Yeah. Yes, I do. I do. Cuz I know that's
been a that's been a question for a long
time on my ear.
>> I am I do smile. I am doing I do have
emotions.
But again, just do
>> you look like you enjoyed the game. I
love the guest. Yes. Absolutely. Why
>> uh just just where I come from. I grew
up in a
harsh area of South LA and
God did his part and just guiding me and
every step that he can possibly uh make
for me and obviously just allowing me to
understand some things or walk into some
things that I didn't really know what I
was getting myself into allowing me to
gain more experience through that.
Romeo, it seems like you've improved and
added to your bag every year of your
career. Is there a certain area of
growth that you're particularly proud
of?
>> Uh just
>> I mean just the reflection of being a
ball player and obviously aligning with
that off the field as well.
>> Yeah. just
just understanding that
as much as being the best player that I
can be for this team is important that
being the best person that I can be off
the field is just as important.
>> Romeo, I'm sorry if this didn't been
asked before, but how is it to come into
a team with the expectations that they
just made a Super Bowl? Like you're
coming in with winning expectations
right away. Does that excite you at all?
>> Yes. Yes. I I I understand what winning
what winning is. I know what it looks
like and
and yeah, I just feel that just based on
what I have done
thus far, um there's a lot more room for
improvement for me to just grow and to
keep understanding what that is like for
myself. So, appreciate it. Thank you,
>> Ray. What do you think you've grown the
most since you entered the NFL?
>> Uh just being a ball player. Um,
obviously understanding the position
very well and continuously just finding
a way to keep understanding it and um,
yeah, just
understanding what teams mean, what
playing special teams means. Just
speeding up the process of being a a
veteran to some degree. It was just a
lot that has went on and I just
understand that moving forward with
these years to come that
I will grow in all areas from football
to life all around.
>> What excites you you know most about
this opportunity as you started to
develop and started Patriots as a place
where you could end up. What was the
most exciting part of that club? Uh the
most exciting part was the
history that this
organization has and it's a lot of
winning football and
playing in this league.
>> The statistical factors is one thing.
Maybe someone's getting some individual
accolade is another. But it ultimately
comes out of weather and I think that's
perfect. What excites you about the wide
receiver group as well where it felt
like last year even Mick Digs here was
moved more than it was any individuals.
What do you see from that group and is
that a factor as well in any work for
them and and Drake?
>> Say that over time.
>> Uh Drake as well. Um in addition to the
wide rece group, what what stands out to
you?
>> Uh just being able to continue to
continue to grow together as a unit.
Um, and I emphasize, you know, just my
time at Green Bay where, you know, all
of us as receivers from myself to Jaden
to Christian or Dantavian Wix, we all
came in as a unit and I feel that with
myself being here, I can be able to
continue that cuz I think I believe they
are.
How about how close this team was to
winning a championship last year? And
does it feel like to you, this group
coming in, you guys are all ready to
take that that next step and finish the
view?
>> Yes, indeed. Yes, indeed. Um
>> Yeah. This
>> Yeah. Why? Why so?
>> Yeah, man. Cuz it's it's experience all
around the room from
from the from it can be from from the
oldest guy in the room going down. It's
just experience all around and
again
it'll it'll only get better moving
forward.
>> I'm excited, man. I kept it right.
>> Dennis Last, what what do you want
Patriots fans to know about like who are
you as a player and an individual and
what do you hope to put on tape?
>> Um,
New England.
uh will get to know someone who is very
grounded, who is very humble
and most importantly true to themselves,
which comes in some form of self
selfrespect, authenticity you may say,
and just knowing that I'm here to work
and I'm not here to
be here for
anything other good. So,
>> thanks.
>> Y
kind of feels like a fan reunion a
little bit. How much did you get to know
Zach Core when you guys were in
Tennessee?
>> Man, Zach is a guy that's, you know, I
mean, just me speaking on the kind of
like the journey, but like just so proud
of him because, you know, when he first
got to Tennessee or when Braves first
came to Tennessee, he was like I think
maybe quality control assistant coach or
something like that. So, to be able to
work his way up and obviously be the DC
now. Uh we talked on the phone last
night and I kind of just told him that
like you guys did an awesome job uh
without obviously with the circumstances
with obviously coach T and things like
that. So uh just awesome to see his
growth and um I think that's one thing
that you'll probably notice about Brael
like most of the guys that are here read
his book who was assistant coach now
he's running the secondary like they all
been brought up in this system and this
culture and uh you know we're all going
to be speaking the same language in that
way. How important was it for you to
come all things being equal to a
contending team?
>> It's important for me because you know I
play more play more than likely. Uh so
want to be a part of a team that you
know you know have the opportunity like
I said I think it was big for me. I
think something that I enjoyed being
Chicago uh was obviously Caleb Williams
was an extended quarterback really great
quarterback. um you know being a part of
that it's like one of the hardest things
to get right you know in the NFL
everybody's trying to do that and uh New
England has it right with Drake May
obviously um uh you know MVP runner up
he had he had a great year last year uh
so I'm excited to be able to play with
him uh but like I said also to be able
to play with you know some of the piece
you know this team has on defense who I
think uh played really well last year
especially even in the Super Bowl so
excited to be able to join them and try
to uh add my game to this group. Talking
about your experiences, what's been the
the key to your sustained success?
>> Uh, a lot of prayer. Um, I would
definitely, you know, got to give credit
to God on a lot of that, especially when
it comes to health. Um, but also too, I
would just, you know, a lot of
preparation. Um, right off his offseason
training, the way I train, um,
some of just, you know, natural guy
given ability to be able to go get the
ball, uh, playing the ball in the air.
Um, you know, I think my game is very
wellrounded and well-rounded with what I
can do. You know, I'm not a guy that
just plays in the bag and pick the ball
off. Like, I've had plenty of years
where I've had 100 tackles, you know
what I mean? I almost had 100 tackles
last year, even leading the league in
interceptions. So, uh, I like to be able
to mix it up uh, and do a lot of things
in my game and hopefully I can bring
that to uh, New England.
>> How much pride do you take in Dr. You
never?
>> I take a lot of pride in that uh,
because like I said, say my preparation,
my routine. Uh, you know, I I I try for
great pro. I try to, you know, do things
the right way, uh, at all times. And,
uh, that's one of the first things that
I'm going to try to do when I get here
is just earn the respect of my teammates
and the coaches. I mean, I I know a lot
of them, but uh, the people that don't
know me, try to earn my ear earn that
respect uh, about how I handle myself
every single day in the building,
outside of the building, um, in the
classroom, on the field, whatever it may
be. Um, because at the end of the day,
man, this business I'm, you know, we're
all here to serve, but that's that's my
main mission. I'm here to serve uh this
team, my teammates, the coaches, uh the
fans, you know, in every single way.
>> Kevin, they feel everything else goes
wrong for agency. It seems like you're
going to join a secondary that could be
really, really, I mean, honestly, dirty
in the NFL. So, how excited does that
make you to have the potential shut down
another team's passing offense like
that?
>> Yeah, I mean, like I said before, I know
um everybody kind of talked about the
relationship I got with Braves. think um
something else that really that really
intrigued me outside of obviously this
team just goes to Super Bowl last year
but the the secondary the pieces that to
play with here obviously Christian
Gonzalez is one of the best corners in
this league already um but also Carlton
Davis been a really good player in this
league for a long time so you got to
play with two really good corners who
has length uh you know can really shut
down both sides of the field uh but then
you also have a top niggle uh Marcus
Jones in the middle and uh you know
Craig Woodson with the guy who I watched
last year um cuz obviously you know got
a lot of relationships in this building
so I was tuned in to a lot of the games
last year um a guy that I really seen
improve out throughout the year and I
mean he played his behind off um in the
Super Bowl. Uh so I'm excited to be able
to play with him and uh try to you know
give him as much as I can as far as
knowledge of the game. Um just you know
like I said do what I can to try to help
this team to be the best and hopefully
I'm that you know final piece to make
this a top secondary in the league.
>> Do you enjoy mentoring a young player
like Craig?
>> Uh do I enjoy it? Yeah. I mean, like I
said, I think um it is all about serving
uh serving the next guy, serving his
team, doing what I can. I don't just
purposely try to say, "Hey, I'm going to
be your leader or nothing like that."
It's just more like it's a natural
thing, you know? I mean, if he has
questions, I'm going to ask questions. I
mean, he's going to uh you know, I'm
going answer any questions. I'm going be
there for him. We're going to watch film
together. Like, I'm a big guy like
trying to get the team together, uh the
group together to watch film and stuff
like that. So, we'll get into all that
once we start playing ball. But, um but
yeah, like I said, I when I was a young
player, I was like a sponge. I wanted to
learn from every guy, um, coach, player.
I wanted to know when to when when the
the the top guys on the team were
getting in the facility in the morning,
what was your routine? What was your,
you know, out of the building routine
when you get massages and stuff like
that? So, uh, I'm going try to be that
that type of guy for this team.
>> Do you see Craig as the ascending
player? I mean, still trying to even
reach greater heights.
>> I mean, absolutely. I mean, the guy was
just a rookie last year, I think. But to
be a rookie and, you know, basically
play and start every single game, uh,
that's going to be big for his growth.
Uh, so yeah, I definitely see him as an
extended player. I think he's good can
be a really good player. Um, as long as
he's healthy, keep doing what he's
doing.
>> What were you first you were there for
Free Will's first year in Tennessee? How
did you see his coaching style um evolve
over his six years and now as you watch
from afar last year?
>> He seems a lot more tame. Uh,
I would say uh no, I mean Ray's first
year in in Tennessee, I think. Um, I
mean, we was coming off a year we had
made it to the playoffs and went to like
the second round. Um, so it wasn't
necessarily a rebuild, but I do think
like he came in and changed our culture
immediately. Um, I've told this story a
little bit, but I remember our first
team meeting with Vable. Uh, we had like
our first OTAA practice and it was kind
of like a jog through de
kind of run and O line jog it out. and
Taylor Lewan, who was our top uh one of
the best left tackles in the league at
the time. And uh I want to say he was
like in the middle of contract
negotiations or something like that. And
he ripped him like you you talking about
you done this this and you jogging and
like you need to run full speed and it
was like whoa. And it was kind of like a
shock to everybody because it was like
man that's our top player basically. And
uh he was just ripping into like the
first thing he had kind of said and I
think he kind of just set the tone of
like everybody in this building will be
held accountable. So if you're not if
you're the top guy, you're not saying
you need to do if you're the young guy.
So I think uh he's always been just
holding everybody accountable. He's
always been team first and uh to see him
from then obviously to all the games and
the all the you know things that we've
accomplished there uh to see him here
last year to be able to make it to the
Super Bowl like I was telling people
Chicago like literally telling people
during training camp like watch out for
New Enged
and it's going to have success. So uh
nothing none of this is uh is surprising
at all. Is that is that
>> Yeah. Is that what you think makes him a
great coach or what else do you think
makes him such a good coach?
>> I just think it's uh just who he is. I
think it's um first and foremost just I
think the pedigree that he comes in with
um you know obviously winning a bunch of
Super Bowls here especially when we
Tennessee like that's the first thing
you kind of already gives him
credibility of what he's saying because
obviously he excuse me he knows how to
get it done. Uh he knows what it takes.
He knows what it looks like. So it's
very easy to buy in in that aspect. So
uh but also then it's just you know
being a leader uh but then also being
very personable. I think he does a great
job of trying to do better relationships
with everybody your family knows your
kids names and stuff like that because I
think personally just being a coach um
it's very easy or it's easier to be able
to get more out of a player when a
player knows that you actually care
about. You know what I mean? Like I
think that sometimes we know this
business is transactional in a way like
this. I mean it is a business but at the
same time uh this is the human business
and I think when you can develop
relationship with somebody on a
personable level it's very easy to be
able to hold them accountable and to try
to get more out of them. So I think he
does a great job of doing all those
things.
>> Did you ever get I haven't looked up yet
but it's like you look up a little bit
and it's like man you've made it to 11
years in in in this league, however many
career interceptions and um it's all
just been my work and preparation just
staying humble and uh now you're good.
Yeah.
like
>> Yeah, man. It's been a great
relationship. I think uh you know,
starting in 2018, um having all those
great years in Tennessee, um those just
special years, you know, like you said
with Rays, whether it was Derry, Henry,
AJ, all the guys, we had so much fun.
And um even when I left, uh you know,
Tennessee, we've always stayed in
contact. Um
Brael still gets to Nashville a little
bit, so I still have my place there,
too. We go to like the same country
clubs, so I see him a lot. Um, I know
his sons very well, Tyler and Carter.
Uh, so we we kept in contact over the
years and things like that. Not
necessarily knowing that we were going
to be able to join forces again. Uh, but
like I said, that's just talks about the
person that he is and uh the great
relationship that we do have.
>> He is for sure. Uh, I think he said he
used to caddy when he was younger. So,
we, you know, I
>> that's what I'm saying.
>> And I think he he lives next to a
country club too now in Nashville. But
uh but no uh our relationship is really
great and um he's definitely the better
golfer for sure.
>> How many more years do you think you
want to play or what do you think you
have left in you,
>> man? Uh it's hard for me to put a limit
on it, a number on it, you know. I just
feel like when when God says that I'm
done playing, I think I'll be done. And
I think I'll know when I'm done. Uh as
long as I continue to play at a high
level, I'm going continue to play. uh as
long as a team uh like New England
values me and values what I bring to the
field and off the field, then I'll
continue to go. But, you know, and I
said this even last year uh before my
season in Chicago, like you know, every
year at this point in my career is year
to year. You know what I mean? Like
that's how I approach it. Um at the end
of the day, I'm going to put everything
uh into it as if it's going to be my
last year. And I think that's how I'm
going to just stay focused and and stay
hungry and stay humble. Uh that every,
you know, every game, every snap, and
every year could be a last. So just
treat it as such.
>> Kevin, congratulations on 11 years.
That's
>> Thank you. Thank you.
>> It is. Trust me.
>> Uh that being in the case with three
years to be 35, be 36. I'm good at math.
>> Yeah, you are. It sounds like it.
>> And this will probably be your last
thought. Are you tracing a championship?
Because you will go to a team that
wasn't a good This is a movie. You're
coming here to win a play.
>> No, absolutely. Uh I said this about I
think before you came over here, but uh
no, you're good. Uh, I had basically two
teams that I wanted to play for, you
know, this off seasonason. Obviously,
you know, with the year we had in
Chicago, that was going to be the first
option. And once I see that that wasn't
going to work out, it was New England,
you know what I mean? And didn't
necessarily know if it was going to work
out, but going into the offseason, going
into like the combine, talking to my
agent, like those are the two teams that
I want to play for. Um, because I think
the hardest thing that you can get in
this league is the quarterback situation
good. Um, and I think New England
definitely has that with a, you know,
MVP runner up in the second year. I
think Dre May Drake May is a phenomenal
player. Um, I've heard nothing but great
things about him, um, from most people
in in the organization even before I got
here. Um, and like you said, this
defense has a lot of great pieces. So, I
just want to be, uh, somebody that's
going to add on to it, uh, and just, you
know, bring everything that I have, uh,
that I've learned over the years and try
to just serve this group as best as I
can
>> because you're a server. when Mike Clay
here went and got a veteran safety about
the Harrison.
>> Yes. Yes.
>> Are you now his new Rodney Harrison? Is
that what's happening there?
>> No. I And I'm pretty sure y'all know all
about Brain and all his rules. He don't
like make comparisons and stuff like
that. Uh no, I don't want to compare
myself to Rodney. I think Rodney was a
was a phenomenal player. We're good
friends. I talk to him all the time. Uh
especially because he do the Sunday
night football, so we'll see each other
all the time. But I just want to be me.
I think that'll be enough. Uh I want to
continue to uh I mean take the ball
away. that that's what I do best. Take
the ball away, get turnovers. Uh but in
that way, I definitely want to be able
to be that veteran presence on the back
end on this team. Uh to try to continue
to help this team and help the culture
stay what it is, and that's a winning
culture.
>> I apolog
uh coming in to this New England, how
you can make an impact here.
>> Yeah. Uh I think I'm one of the more uh
most well-rounded uh safeties in this
league. You know, I think everybody
knows me for uh my ball hawking talents,
catching all interceptions, things like
that. But, you know, not last year,
obviously, I had 93 tackles, but the two
years prior to that, I had 130 tackles,
120 something tackles. So, I can get in
the box, uh, play the run very well, but
also my strong suit is being be able to
be back there, be that center fielder,
and be able to take the ball away from
teams. So, I take a lot of pride in
that. Um, and really whatever this
coaches ask me to do, I'm going to do it
to the best of my ability. So, I think
I'm very rare with
>> in that secondary. Another guy who um
>> likes to, you know, take the ball away
is Christian Gonzalez. What's your
impression of him and what's your level
of excitement to kind of play back there
with him?
>> Yeah, he's one of the best corners in
this league. You know, when I first got
to Chicago, Jaylen Johnson, uh I think
he was just getting a new contract
coming off a Pro Bowl and stuff like
that. Uh that was my first real
opportunity to play with like a true
shutdown, number one corner. Um I see
Christian Gonzalez in that same light.
Um like I said, he's a phenomenal
player. I mean, he has lymph, he has
speed. Um, I haven't talked to him just
yet personally, but he ain't got to
worry about me shading to his side of
the field. Like, you can lock that stuff
down and we'll we'll go to the other
side. We'll cover the rest. Uh, but no,
I think he's a phenomenal player.
>> Kevin, the uh the NFDA, they have all
like the snap count players and stuff.
They said you missed only two snaps the
entire season. Yeah. Do you remember
when they were?
>> Yeah, they were like a certain goal line
package that uh Jaquan Brisker was the
only safety in. So, I came out on those
plays, but it wasn't missed for any
injuries. Like I said, I'm normally used
to playing basically every single snap
of every game. I've been doing that my
entire career, except for my rook year
where I didn't start every game. Uh but
yeah, like I said, I take pride in being
available, you know. Um I think
availability is your best ability. And
uh you know, you can't you can't make
the team. You can't make plays in in the
in in the cold tub. So, uh I try to try
to do my best to uh be available and
that's with the preparation, just my
recovery routine and everything.
>> Over the course of your um now it's your
11th year. What has stood out to you
about how the league has changed? Is it
like the nutrition? Is it the social
media? Like what what stands out to you
about just how being NFL player has
changed?
>> I think it's No, it changes all the
time, but it's in multiple ways. I think
it's like the way offenses operate, you
know what I mean? Like I want to say
earlier in my career, like it was a lot
more tight end sets and then everything
was just like spread open all 11
personnel. Now you're starting to see
even more
like you're starting to see like this
this change in like the tight ends like
so a lot of teams that you used to play
it was like you had your one blocking
tight end your one tight end that was
like more like the receiver receiving
type tight end. So you kind of easily
match up personnel like okay we know
what this guy does best what this guy
doesn't but nowadays some of these tight
ends are just like they could block they
could catch so it's kind of hard uh to
be able to tell like for example like in
Chicago you they drafted a guy coast in
love last year well I think personally
he's going to be all pro probably if not
next year the year at the next uh who's
a really good tight end um but that's a
little bit different I think now on
defense it's like it's not really lot of
like three linebackers on the field
anymore uh everybody's basically base
defense It's 5 DBs. If you can get six
DBs out there, you probably try to get
six if if the the the sixdB can hit like
a linebacker. Uh so it's just trying to
get as much speed out there on the field
as possible because it's a passing
league nowadays. Every every rule,
every, you know, penalty is to get the
offense in the end zone. Um so trying to
get as much speed out there. So the game
has definitely changed in a lot of ways.
I mean, we can have a deeper talk about
this, but probably don't got enough time
for it. But it's definitely changed.
>> Yeah, it's really cool. Um, they haven't
been here too long, but enjoying the
area, enjoying Foxboro so far, and you
know, just the people here have been
really welcoming, so I'm excited.
>> What's it like? I know you were
teammates with Morgan Moses. That play
any faster in your decision to come
here, and did you get to speak with him
during that decision?
>> Yeah, I would say it definitely played a
factor, you know, um, just Morgan being
the type of guy he is.
>> Um, you know, I knew I could trust his,
uh, his opinion on this place. Um, so
yeah, just after talking to him for a
while, it definitely uh played a factor
into me coming here.
>> You excited when you signed?
>> Yeah, I think so. Yeah.
>> Elijah, what was your free agency
process like? And how heavy were the
Patriots after the whole time? Was it a
a long drawn out thing? Quick.
>> Yeah, I would say the uh free agency
process, it was it was different. You
know, my first time uh doing that. Uh
I'd say, you know, a decent amount of
teams were interested. Um but you know
making a decision what it came down to
was just um you know going to a place
that had you know an established uh
culture of winning you know established
culture of of um you know guys who just
love the game and love playing for each
other and obviously the coaching staff
as well. So you know all those factors
kind of came into playing in and uh in
the decision coming here and I'm
excited.
>> I know you played left guard, right
guard, right behind role. If you were
asked to play left guard here, would you
be comfortable making that move back
over there? Yeah, I think so. Um, you
know, I'm the type of guy I'm a team
team first type of player. Um, like you
said, I played at left guard before, so
I don't mind uh going over there. I
haven't had talks on where yet I'm going
to play. Um, but I'm excited regardless.
>> Why you nice to meet you?
>> How you doing? Nice to meet you.
>> Um, obviously you've had kind of a star
cross career with a number of injuries.
So,
>> how frustrating and disappointing has
that been for you?
How confident are you going forward with
it that boot?
>> We can never predict.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Mhm. Yeah. I mean, it's a
it's definitely a hard process to go
through, you know. I feel like any
athlete who's been through injuries
understands that. Um and it's upset or
it used to upset me, you know, cuz I'm
playing at such a high level, you know,
for my team. Balling out and everything
and then going down hurts not being able
to play uh on the field with my team and
my brother. So, um you know, that's just
something I've had to learn to deal
with. But I think going into the future,
you know, I'm feeling really confident
in myself and really confident in this
team and this training staff, you know,
to to get me through multiple seasons
here and I'm excited about it.
>> How many weekly difficult was it during
the times where you you're trying to
crap kill you?
>> Yeah, I know. Yeah. Yeah, it it
definitely sucks. You know, you kind of
enter this dark place a little bit, but
luckily you have a great support system
with family and friends, you know, old
teammates as well.
>> Awesome. Um, but I'm the type of guy,
you know, I won't let anything kind of
get me down or or put me down as well.
So, you know, I'm the type of guy I love
to work. I feel like I have a good work
ethic, so I was able to push through
that. Um, and yeah, like I said, man,
I'm excited to bring that energy here.
>> Jeep, have you changed at all the way
you train? Have you tried to modify to
maybe I don't know if that was something
that you you thought might be an issue?
>> Yeah. Yeah, I've had a lot of
conversations uh over this past uh
season and offseason. Um you know, just
different things to take for my body,
different ways to take care of my body,
little things here and there. Happy
Baric Chambers, stuff like that. Um so,
I definitely been doing a lot of
research and I'm working with a great
staff where I'm training at right now.
Uh helping me out with that, too.
>> Where are you at with your latest
injury?
>> Uh I'm feeling really good. Uh almost
100%. Um by the time I get to OTAAS, it
should be should be good.
>> Why is this a nice match? you and New
England. What What appeals to you about
coming here?
>> Like I said before, you know, I think uh
just the winning culture that this place
has had. Um you know, playing against
these guys, you know, I've seen it
firsthand. Um and then just talking to
other guys on the team, you know, as
well, just hearing how everybody vibes
with each other in the locker room. You
know, when you look back at this past
offseason, a lot of people say, you
know, when I ask them how'd you guys get
to the Super Bowl, a lot of them say
it's just because everybody vibes with
each other and like loves each other.
So, you know, I feel like you can't go
wrong with with uh making a decision.
>> How do you describe this day? I mean,
it's you weren't drafted, you're not a
rookie. You're coming to a new place.
How do you describe this day?
>> Yeah, it's it's definitely a surreal
feeling. You know, it's not the same as
getting drafted somewhere, but you know,
this opportunity, my first time in PJ,
got to pick where I wanted to go play.
Um, and that's a blessing in itself. you
know, I'm super grateful that the
Patriots, you know, wanted to get me and
uh I wanted to come here as well and,
you know, win games in my career and
play at a high level. So, I'm excited to
do that.
>> What do you want Patriots fans to know
about you? I
>> mean, I just want them to know I'm a,
you know, I'm a low-key guy who just
likes to come in and and, you know, vibe
with my teammates and and coaches and
just put my head down and work. That's
all, you know, I really want to come in
and do and obviously create a great
relationship with everybody in the
building and all the fans as well. How
much does it mean in 2021? Did you think
there's a possibility that you could be
coming here?
>> No man, not at all. Uh I'll be real with
you. You know, like playing for the Jets
for the past five years, you develop,
you know, I'll be real with you guys, a
certain type of hate, you know, for for
this team. Uh which is really, you know,
I'll keep it real, but uh you know, at
the end of the day, this league is a
business. You know, I have to do what's
best for myself and my family. Like I
said, this place has a great culture of
winning and just playing at a high level
always. Um, so yeah, I mean it was it
was a no-brainer.
>> And what do you think? You sound a
pretty uh unique contract and a lot of
stuff built into per game roster.
>> How comfortable were you with that deal
and that setup?
>> Mhm.
>> Yeah, I would say I I was really
comfortable. You know, I really uh
>> I really I got to give a lot of credit
to my agent, you know. Um he's been with
me through and through, you know, always
keeping my head up high. Um, and you
know, there's obviously things in the
contract that are there for a reason,
you know, given my history, but um, you
know, I don't mind that when all I get
to do is come in and play football for a
great team.
>> How excited are you how excited are you
to protect Drake May? What was your
impression of him from a farm?
>> Yeah, really excited, man. Um,
obviously, you know, playing against him
and seeing him firsthand, I've seen what
he can do. Um, and, you know, besides
him being a great football player, I've
heard he's a great guy as well, too. So,
I think that's very important to have a
leader like that um for the team, you
know, QB who's plays at a high level,
but also is able to connect well with
his teammates.
>> Elijah, how much does it mean to you to
be reunited with Morgan Moses and how
much did he mean to you when you guys
were together in New York?
>> Yeah, man. Uh it it definitely means a
lot. You know, Morgan, that's my guy. He
was with me my rookie year. He
definitely coached me up on a lot of
things. Um and you know, when you're a
rookie, you need that veteran presence.
So, he was definitely there with me
along with some other guys as well.
Well, Morgan, I think, you know, he's a
great guy. I think highly of him and I
excited to play with him again.
>> Penc process. How extensive were your
conversations with Mike Green? What were
your impressions of him?
>> Mhm.
>> Yeah. Well, you know, I could only talk
to him uh you know during the time we
could talk to coaches. So, uh it was
very little, but you know, just off
first impression um you know, he really
impressed me with his uh with his
questions and him answering my questions
as well. you know, like I said, I think
he's done a great job of establishing uh
that winning culture here again. You
know, obviously after doing it after one
year. Um, and then obviously seeing what
he did in Tennessee as well. You know,
if you could come and play for a guy
like that, why don't you?
>> When you think about your own injury
history, how much does it count to you
to have a coach who can put himself in
your shoes, so to speak, as a player and
know? Yeah, I think it's uh I think it's
really uh significant for me, you know,
like a a player or a coach who, you
know, as a former player understands
what these players go through each and
every day throughout the league, whether
it's um injuries or, you know, just
being drained from a long season. So,
you know, when you get to come and play
for a coach that that cares about you,
not only as a player, but as a person as
well first, that that means a lot.
>> You mentioned the hatred. Do you get
much grief from friends and family when
you said in order to wiggle this?
>> Yeah, for sure, man. Uh obviously uh all
my friends in New York, you know, or all
my family, you know, they they all have
love. They all understand it. You know,
some of the fans are a little upset,
which I get, you know, I'd be upset,
too. But I wish nothing for the best for
that team. You know, I'll keep on
rooting for them and the guys over there
as as long as we don't play them. You
know, when they don't when they play us,
obviously it's about us.
>> You feel like you probably made it to
the NFL now to the Patriots and not the
Jets.
>> I wouldn't say that. Uh, you know,
coming to NFL rookie year was
definitely, yeah, I got you. It was
definitely a surreal experience, but
like you said, man, the something about
the Patriots, man, they just have a
history of winning, you know. Then you
add Rabel to that as well with with Greg
May and the type of guys that they
brought in here, it's really special.
>> How would you describe your playing
style here?
>> I would say just tough and nasty, you
know. Um, I'm the type of guy, you know,
you got to play with that type of
tenacity uh in the trenches. Um, so I'm
excited about I'm excited to come uh
come and compete, you know, with a good
D line group as well. I think they're
going to push me. I'm going to push them
and I'm excited about it.
>> Are you surprised at all though? Who
plot everything after the game and the
Super Bowl around Will Campbell as a
fellow offensive line?
>> Yeah, man. I think it's uh you know, I
think that's just a lot of the media,
you know, who would have never been in
in a player's shoes before. You know, I
think I think highly of Will, you know,
let's looking at from LSU and last year.
I think he's a great player. you know, I
think he was a rookie last year who was
dealing with injuries as well. You know,
for him to be able to play through that
and play in the Super Bowl, like I said,
I think very highly of that and uh
commend him for that as well.
>> Well, what do you know about the the
style or the identity um of this
offense? How much have you looked into
that? How much have you talked to people
about that?
>> Yeah, I looked into it a little bit. Um
haven't, you know, too much. Haven't
gotten into it too much. Um but just
talking to, you know, all the coaches
and everything,
>> I liked what they had to say today. Um,
hey, you know, like I said, I'm excited
about it. I've seen how the O line
plays. You know, I like uh Big Mike over
there, Mo, Will, all that. So, I'm
excited to get in that room and work
with them.
>> With with some of the the lineman that
you just mentioned, you know, the team
just signed a fullback and Reggie. Um,
Julian is apparently a very good walking
tight end. Does that get you excited as
an offensive lineman? Like, it it looks
like, you know, the teams try to add
pieces so that you can be like a a
physically imposing group.
>> Yeah. No, it's definitely uh that
definitely gets me excited, man. You
know, when you're old lineman, obviously
we love to run the ball like to, you
know, pass the ball, too, obviously, but
running ball is in our DNA, you know.
So, when you have guys who could block
and you had a fullback to that as well,
who who likes to get nasty in the run
game, that's exciting.
>> Have you had a chance to talk to Josh
McDaniels at all yet or
>> a little bit? Yeah. Uh it's been just so
busy today, you know, just trying to
make my rounds, but uh I'm excited to
get all the coach's numbers and hit them
up individually. after the injury before
the season. Did you rehab at the
facility? Were you on your own or what
was your last year like?
>> Yeah. So, I rehabbed at the facility
during the season. Um, and I did that,
you know, because I was nominated the
captain by my teammates. So, I felt
obligated.
>> Yeah. This was my first time and I felt
obligated to be around my teammates and
continue to build relationship with my
teammates and everybody in the building.
You know, like I said, I I really
enjoyed my time over there. I think
highly of everybody in that building
wish them nothing but the best. Um, but
yeah, I was in my rehab over there and
then now I'm currently in California
doing it. And
>> and where does that stand now? Like is
there a high range when you feel like
you might be able to be on the field?
Will you be able to do mini camp stuff
or anything?
>> Yeah. No, I definitely be able to do all
that mini camp stuff. Um, you know, I
see myself progressing, you know, very
well in this uh in this rehab process,
but by the time I come back for OTAA, it
should be good.
>> Is there a side you prefer to be on? I
know you kind of have played a bunch of
spots.
>> Yeah, I mean, I don't know. It's
interesting, you I feel like once I've
been on one side for for a while, I do
kind of prefer that side. But man, you
give me I don't know a week or two of
practicing on the other side and I'll be
good.
>> And do I ever as a rookie you were on
the left and then the last couple years
you've been on the right side?
>> Yeah. So on the rookie I was left and
then uh I was on the right side my
second year and then like played tackle
a couple games here and there.
What stood out to you most about this
opportunity kind of going through the
process and why why the Patriots and
this particular Taha team and Mo
>> Yeah, I mean honestly I think you know I
had a couple options out there. Um but I
think something that excited me the most
about the Patriots were was that they
were excited about me, you know, so when
you have a team that is excited about
you and you know willing to to go get
you, I think that's really special in
this league. Um, and then also like I've
said plenty of times, the culture
they're building here, it's already been
built here and that Rabel is just
building upon that. I think very highly
of Rael, I think he's a player's coach.
He really understands what the players
go through, you know, loves to get to
know the players as well before, you
know, just coaching them. So, just
talking to him, you know, on Monday was
uh, it definitely got me excited.
>> Something pretty much the entire free
agent class has said is that Brael was a
huge factor. What's specifically about
him? You mentioned players coach like
for him is it the the fact that he knows
what players go through his during
ability like what stood out the most
about him during this process have made
that a big factor for you? Well, I think
like I said like he's, you know, he's a
former player and, you know, a term
coach who kind of understands what we go
through. And when you look at it like
before, you know, last year, I don't
think anybody really expected the
Patriots to go all the way to the Super
Bowl. And when you look at it, there's
there's got to be a main reason for
that. Like, yeah, Drake's talented. they
have, you know, tons of players on the
team, but I think it comes down to
Braville coming in and, you know,
establishing that culture, you know,
where everybody has love for each other,
real love for each other and wants to
play for each other and wants to, you
know, do everything they can on that
field.
>> Do you look at the line that they're all
coming in and like who you've been
playing with, as you mentioned, you kind
of moved around past like does that was
that a factor and do you see yourself
kind of as that last piece that can be a
a truly dominant line?
>> Yeah, man. I wouldn't uh or I would say
I definitely, you know, tuned in to who
was here already and what position I may
be playing, but like I said, I'm a team
first guy, so you know, I was willing to
kind of come in and play wherever on the
line. Um, you know, I would say this O
line was already dominant in itself. You
know, I've played with Morgan Moses. I
know how he plays. I know his his work
ethic. You know, I've heard of Big Mike.
I've seen how he plays. Will Campbell
and all that. So, you know, I'm excited
to come in and uh and add my, you know,
my talents and my work ethic and see
where it takes us.
>> Last thing, you mentioned how good Drake
is. What impresses you most about him
and how excited you to be a part of, you
know, he is further growth. Obviously
finished second, the MVP, so they're
already kind of there, right? Sure.
Yeah.
>> Looking to get obviously that next.
>> Yeah. Yeah, I think, you know, when you
look at Drake's uh play style, you know,
I think uh he's the type of guy who
doesn't get down on himself, you know,
makes a bad play, comes out and, you
know, balls out the next series. And I
think that's very important in this
league. I think you got to have a short
memory, you know, when you make a bad
play. Um but not even just, you know,
the player from Drake M. I think the
person I've heard so many things
through, you know, friends and, you
know, my agency and stuff like that who
represent them like nothing but great
things. So if I come and you know
protect a guy like that, it's worth it.
>> Thanks.
>> Thank you.
>> I have one last word for you. When you
think you've grown, like it's been kind
of an eventful first four or five years
in the NFL. What do you feel like you've
grown since you've been in the room
here?
>> Yeah, I think uh I think just my
mentals, you know, mentally I think I've
grown as a player. Um obviously I think,
you know, physically talent wise, I
think I've gotten better every year,
whether it's, you know, in camp or
playing games. the impression.
>> I think definitely learning how to how
to how to love this game, you know,
because of my injury history. You know,
when you come back and play, you
definitely got to have love for it to go
through all that. So, definitely my love
for the game has grown. And yeah, like I
said, just mentally, you know, there's
kind of like nothing that could
challenge me mentally now, you know,
which I which I think is a is a very
strong suit for me. That makes me think
when you got the news before last
season, it was like how did you take
that? What was that like? You just named
captain and you get this massive blow
up.
>> Yeah. What was going through your head
at that point?
>> Yeah, man. That obviously that was
really tough, you know. Um and that was
probably the worst one only because, you
know, I had uh I had gotten nominated
captain, you know, not by the coaches,
but by my by my teammates. Um and I was
ready to go out there and lead them this
year, you know, no matter what. and then
not be able to to not be able to go out
there and play for my team, you know,
for my brothers. Um, it definitely
sucks, man. Like, I don't think people
realize when you're hurt, you're just
separated from the team, like team
meetings, practices, and all that. So,
it definitely sucks, but like I said,
and then I had a great support system
over there from the guys in the O line
room, my teammates, and even the people
in the building, you know, I have a lot
of respect for those people.
>> Did you know right away when it
happened, or was it something that you
had to kind of get a couple opinions on?
Yeah, I kind of knew right away. Uh,
which sucked, you know, because on
practice I don't want to be on the
field, you know, let everybody kind of
know and worry about me, you know. So, I
kind of just walked off and it was
tough, you know, but I knew what I had
to do. I'd been through the process
before and I was ready to attack the
process again.
>> Yeah. Just do you feel like you're going
to be ready for the start of training
camp and
>> 100%. Yeah.
>> Yeah. And the other question I just had
for you was just going back to left
guard potentially and just how
comfortable I know you moved all around
at the USC, but comfortable do you feel
playing at that spot specifically?
>> Yeah, man. I'd say I feel pretty good.
And you know, it's it's been a little
while since I was over there, but
>> um you know, you give me a couple
practices, couple weeks, I'll be good.
>> Has you had any of those types of
conversations yet?
>> I I haven't yet. Um you know, I'm a team
first guy, so wherever team needs me,
I'm I'm be able to go play there. um
whether it's right guard, left guard,
wherever, you know, I haven't had
conversations yet, but I'm sure we'll
figure that out soon.
>> Elijah, I'm sorry if you've been asked
this before.
>> No, you
>> and I know that you're joining a team
that where the offensive line is under
the microscope. So, how do you feel like
your game can help this offensive line
and turn it around?
>> Yeah, man. I think uh I think you know
just naturally I'm a you know I'm a I'm
a natural athlete you know so I think
for me to come in and with my talents
and my work ethic you know I hope to
bring um great energy here and great
work ethic to a good old line already
you know with Will Campbell Morgan and
and Big Mike you know I've seen how
those guys play I respect how those guys
play so you know I'm not coming here
with any high expectations you know for
the line art itself I'm just coming in
you know ready to work and I'm sure you
know by the end of this year and the
season we'll be proud of ourselves.
>> And how's your body feeling?
>> My body's feeling great, man. I'm
training right now, doing everything
pretty much. No restrictions, you know,
so by the time I come back to OTAA
should be 100.
>> Awesome. Welcome to New England.
>> Thank you, man.
>> Hey, I apologize. I've already been
asked this, but uh you know, a couple
rookies playing key spots last year,
which Wilson guys are going to be
playing with.
>> I don't know how much you got to watch
them last year, how much you get to
watch other offenses or from what you
saw. What were your initial impressions
of of them as rookies?
>> Yeah, I thought they're uh very talented
guys, man. I think for uh for Jared to
never play guard before and then go out
there and do his thing, I think he's
very strong. I think he's a talented
player. I'm excited to play next to him.
And then Will, too, you know, there's a
reason why they got him so early in the
draft, I guess, the year before. So, you
know, just looking at their tape, um you
know, not too much of it, but you know,
when they played against us last or
against the Jets last year, you know, I
got to witness it firsthand. and you
know I liked what I saw and then I was
excited to come in here and work with
the roof.
>> You mentioned chair chaining positions.
You've done that a little bit in your
career. How does that impact a player's
development when you're not, you know,
in a spot kind of just playing?
>> Yeah, I think uh, you know, I think it
impacts it maybe a little bit, you know,
u depending on the player, but I think,
you know, Jared is a naturally gifted
athlete, you know, who could he prove
that he could move, you know, pretty
much anywhere in the interior, you know,
playing lifeguard all season last year.
Um, and then for him to go and play
center this year, I think is a, you
know, I think very highly of that. And
anybody who could do that, man, special
talent in his league.
>> I actually have a mic with ESPN.
>> I don't chance to meet you at that
point.
>> Um, just heard I think I heard you say
no restrictions. I'm sure you
>> No. Yeah. Can you just explain?
>> No. Yeah. So, I currently I do have
restrictions uh training. Um, but you
know, I'm progressing well and when I
come back for OTAA, it should be full
participant early season.
>> Some of those are just freak things like
come out of nowhere. Like
>> how much did your experience with the
injuries want you to just have a fresh
start? Nothing against
>> you know what I mean? But I'm curious
what your mindset was.
>> Yeah, I think for me um I think you you
explained it well. like a fresh start
is, you know, is uh I think what I
needed, you know, and I I appreciate,
you know, the hell out of the Patriots
for for wanting me and me wanting to go
there as well. Um but like you said, you
know, you have when you have free
accidents, you know, it sucks cuz you're
away from the team, but you know, I
really enjoyed my time. Uh you know, the
past 5 years that was a team that
drafted me. I had nothing respect for
everybody in that building, the fans and
all that. You know, I I do hope they win
a lot of games, just not against us. How
much do you know Will Campbell and if
you're playing next to him, which ways
could you go?
>> Yeah, I think uh I think Will Campbell's
a special talent, you know. I think um
you know, in his rookie year, obviously
every rookie here, every rookie has a
whole lot to learn in this league. It's
it's obviously different from college.
The pace, you know, the strength of
guys, but I think he definitely held his
own. um you know, he played against some
really talented guys and I think, you
know, just the fact that he was able to
play pretty much every game, um I think
is is is really good for him and I'm
excited to see him year two.
>> And if you were to play with Omir, which
which ways could you help him?
>> Mhm.
>> Man, I would say um you know, just not
involving technique. I would say, you
know, just mentally stay strong, which I
think he does have that mindset, you
know, um in this league, you got to have
a quick memory. you know, if you get
beat one play, it's a league. It's going
to happen, you know, so you got to move
on. And I think he did a good job of
that last year. And then, you know, for
for um technique-wise, you know, we'll
have to see once I get out there with
him.
>> Obviously, from afar, you've seen the
Patriots change since being drafted,
coaching or older back.
>> Yeah.
>> What are your impressions of this team
now, and how has that sort of changed
when you got into the league?
>> Mhm. I would say, you know, when I got
into the league, uh, you know, I think
they were kind of in, uh, trying to
figure out, you know, where they were
going to go from Tom Brady leaving,
everything like that. But I think, you
know, they were a very good team when we
played them. You know, I think that's
just the culture that's been established
here. You know, the culture of winning.
I think any player that comes in here
still wants to represent that and I've
seen that the past five years. Um, but I
think just with Variable, you know,
being a players, you know, type of guy
and
and, you know, having the love for the
game that he has and then everyone else,
you know, kind of following that, I
think is really special. I think there's
a reason why they went to the Super Bowl
and I think that's why
>> the Jets took you one fist ahead of Matt
Jones when you're working here.
>> I'm curious, do you remember any
interest that the Patriots might have
shown?
>> What sort of draft process and he take
us to Reval? maybe if you ended up here
too.
>> Yeah, I think I recall they had a little
bit of interest. Um, you know, like I
said, it would have been, you know,
great if I had come here, but the Jets
picked me and I was super excited that
the Jets had picked me and I was willing
to give it my all, which I did my past 5
years. Um, but yeah, man, we're here
now. I would have never thought that I'd
be, you know, a Patriot being on the
Jets for the past 5 years, developing,
you know, a certain type of hate for the
Patriots, but we're here now. I'm
blessed and I'm super excited.
Do you plan to to spend the voluntary
program here?
>> Yeah. Yeah, I do. Marine Favorite?
>> Yeah. Yeah, I plan to come here as soon
as we can.
>> Is that like Did you do that with the
Jets where you did you volunteer?
>> Yeah, I pretty much did everything over
there. Yeah. I just feel like if I could
come in and build a relationship with
the guys and the coaching staff, might
as well.
>> Yeah. I'm here with my wife. Uh yeah.
So, this is exciting, man. You know, we
came all the way from California today.
Um, you know, so we're super excited and
just ready to get to work, you know.
>> Hashim. Is there one thing about Boston,
New England that you're looking forward
to?
>> Food experience, anything that come to
mind.
>> Maybe clam chowder. I don't know. Um,
but yeah, man. I think I think you guys
call it the title town, right? So, you
know, it's it's that for a reason. And
you know, I'm kind of excited to come
here and and witness that firsthand, you
know, and be part of that as well and do
everything I can to to make it work.
>> Nice topic. Thank you. Thanks for taking
the time.
>> Yes, sir. Thank you. Appreciate it.
>> Thank you.
>> Welcome to New England.
>> Happy to be here, man. I appreciate
that.
>> How How did this whole process play out
for you? And I know it was relatively
quickly and you know, you were I think
you were think you might have been the
first name that that Mike and Elliot
went out. Mhm.
>> What was your experience?
>> Um, my experience was me training and my
agent handling everything and then, you
know, he would check in periodically and
just tell me what's going on and I'll
take that information and talk with my
fiance about it and think about what's
the best decision to go about what we're
going to do.
>> Um, what sort of preconceived ideas did
you have about the Patriots from the
outside?
>> Honestly, honestly, zero. I've always
known the Patriots to be winning. they
usually on the winning side since I've
been in the league. Um, I'm also heard
things about Rabel and I heard a bunch
of positive stuff because I've had guys
play for him with him.
So, I mean, I've always heard positive
things about this this organization.
>> One of the things that attracted a lot
of guys last year was Rap was the
opportunity to play. What What are some
things that you heard about him from
some of those guys that made you say,
you know, I want to be a part of this. I
want to join them. Well, just he he he
likes to be involved a lot and I I
appreciate that. And he's a dlama, so he
he understands how to be grit and be
nasty in there. And then uh Jeff Sers
would say like, you know, sometimes
he'll go out there and do the drills
with you and and he'll be the dummy. You
work on them. But like stuff like that
is like it's kind of what I like.
>> There was um there's video of him
working with Bar last year and kind of
going and kind of going back like that.
He's really I was he really gets into
it. Does that
>> from the outside does that I don't know
this is an outsiders does that how much
does that matter like having a guy who
sees a position who knows what you're
going through?
>> Yeah, a lot. He can he knows what I'm
going through. He can relate. He knows
the ins and outs. He knows like if I
what I see he's able to understand what
I see
>> and and how I react based on what
lineman does. So I mean stuff like that
you you have to appreciate and uh I'm
excited to work with him.
>> Obviously sacks I I think again this is
my own experience here. sacks can be
kind of underrated or overrated.
>> This is a team that kind of struggled at
times to get consistent pressure on the
pass. How much of a part of that is your
game and and how much of a priority do
you put on getting up?
>> I mean, that's my top priority. I I I
put given all my focus into it. Um
that's all I I train for really, you
know, playing I I don't have to train
for the run because, you know, it's
second nature. You've been doing all
your life. But pass rushing, I'm always
trying to hold it in, watching extra
film and and doing what I can. I feel
like I've I've done a good job, you
know. Uh, my sack numbers were pretty
good last year. Uh, my QB hits were
great. Now this year, I want to turn
some of those I had like 25 QB hits. So
hopefully I can turn some of those QB
hits into sacks.
>> What, if at all did Rabbel say your role
with this team?
>> We haven't gotten to that part yet, but
I I know right now I'm be outside
linebacker
>> and uh I'll be opposite of of Harold.
>> Okay. Do you know anything about the
position coach, Mike Smith? He was a guy
who spent a lot of time last couple
years really working with a lot of guys.
I know he Caleb who was here last year
since moved on spoke very very highly of
him. Do you know him at all?
>> No, I've got I've gotten to know him
over the over the course of these um you
know couple days of talking on the phone
and now they meet him in person. But I
do know he likes big ends and I'm a big
in because you know I started off as a a
DTackle, lost weight and now I'm a big
ass in. So I'm excited to work with
Mike. I know I know he's going to do me
right.
>> Do you feel like you could move back
inside if you had to like and I'm not
talking about a consistent basis but
like if they needed Hey, we're going to
work a little rotation here. We're going
to have you bump inside for golf snaps.
>> Yeah, I think I could. Um I think I'm
I'm very versatile. I think with that
versatility, I think I'm good at what I
do. So, um I think I can kick inside if
they need me. If one day some team need
gain 30 pounds and try 80 tackle again,
I'll try. I can do that.
>> Do you know any guys in this roster, any
sort of connections? Any any guys who
are here that you know you're looking to
connect with again or?
>> Um yeah, I don't know if he's still
going to be here, but the Munford, know
him. Um There's a great guy
>> there. There's my dog. We we played
together for like three years in
college. Um Tayvon, I know we we have
that Ohio State connection. I was
talking [__] against him last year when
I played against y'all uh when I was at
Tennessee. Um so those two guys are
probably the most the most two I'm
familiar with.
>> One of the things that we've talked
about up here a lot over the last year
plus with the team building process in
Rael is that he is um has an affinity
obviously for house day.
>> Obvious. Did that come up at all in the
process? Like, hey, you know what?
>> A little a little bit like knowing that
he he he he gets the culture. He he
knows how like we're brought up. So,
>> it kind of played a part.
>> And it's just funny. We we got um B
who's going to be here obviously
>> he goes back with him. There were a
couple guys. Spain goes back with him to
Tennessee.
>> It's not it doesn't seem to be a
coincidence that he goes after kind of
reel guy talked about so far. Maybe the
connection with Ohio State. Um
>> great. Thank you. I appreciate you.
Thank you.
>> Hey, what excites you most about this
opportunity? We kind of going through
the process and the Patriots were a part
of that. What kind of stood out you as
being the main selling black careers as
to why this was the place you wanted to
end up?
>> Um, got to go with Braves, man. I' I've
heard nothing but positivity from so
many different players. Um, especially
uh the guys that that played for him at
Tennessee. They were they were jokingly
making the comment like, "Man, I got to
get to to to the Patriot Braves." But I
think that's probably the driving force.
>> Obviously, you shared a position with
him and he has has an area expertise in
that particular area. Is it more that or
is it more how he handles players? What
are the biggest driving factors that
make guys want to play for for Brook
Graves more? So, do you think because of
how he understands your position or is
it more just totality?
>> It's both totality. How how he
understands players, how he uh
understands the position one, and you
know, how he gets to to motivate guys,
how he coaches them. Um, he has that
that that Buckeye uh package to him that
I understand and is what I'm kind of
used to. So, I'm looking forward to to
seeing how he is in action.
>> You sign you signed really early uh in
the process. What what was so appealing
about you to come here to New England?
>> Uh I was saying to him uh a lot of it
was raves and then this place like this
has been a winning culture for so many
years. They literally just was in the
Super Bowl a month ago. So, I mean it's
pretty easy I think to to want to play
here.
>> And for those who don't know you, What
are the strengths in your game and what
do you bring to the Patriots?
>> Um, I bring in toughness. Um, I'm play
balls to the wall. You know, I'm I'm I'm
always looking to try to run through
somebody face. Uh, I'm trying to stick
my nose in it. I'm I'm I'm aggressive.
So, I think that's what I I think I do
best.
>> How much do you know about the Pats uh
Pat? Obviously some good players uh
potentially next to you normally
expression barry.
>> I've known I've known a little bit from
afar. You know, you just you see them,
you watch I watch a bunch of Patriots
tape this past year, ironically, because
we just end up playing the same team.
So,
>> I know how good these guys can be.
>> When you look at the defense right now,
what do you see and how do you kind of
put it into their scheme and what they
do? Is that something that you look at?
>> I haven't I haven't got I got a chance
to look super in depth in the defensive
total, but maybe just the the outside
linebacker room. And uh I see a bunch of
talented guys, man. big uh they're
smart. You know, you got different
flavors from from big rug guys to to
speed guys. So, that's kind of why I
pione the most.
>> How big a factor was winning? And do you
feel like this team obviously right in a
Super Bowl, but you feel like you're
right there in terms of winning a
championship? And maybe the guys in this
room, the draft class, push this team
over the top.
>> Uh it's not for me to say if we're right
there towards winning championship. I
don't know what that feels like. Um um I
think personally for me, step one is
trying to get to the playoff for the
first time. It's going to my eighth
season and uh I haven't been to the
playoffs yet and then I know this team
just came out of the Super Bowl. So, you
know, hopefully I can be part of the
driving force that they can go back to
the Super Bowl and I can be a big part
of them winning the Super Bowl. So,
>> you played against Drake last year
towards the end of the year and and
>> I played against I played against him
twice actually.
>> I played against him in Tennessee. Uh
played pitch in Tennessee and I played
against you guys in Baltimore too.
>> What are what are your thoughts about
him?
uh smart, decisive, um just a lot of arm
talent is what I noticed.
>> You were you were with him the rookie
year for his like insane play and he ran
around for 20 seconds, right?
>> Was it sentiment in rookie year, right?
You guys went in OT. Is that the one
where he hit from Andre? I'm trying to
remember.
>> No, I don't. When was the rookie year?
>> You were far last.
>> 24.
>> No, I was in Seattle. So, no.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. I I didn't play because rookie
year. Also, you played him twice last
year. You said
>> I played him twice. I got traded.
>> Oh, if you ask right. Played him twice.
>> Yeah.
>> Interesting.
>> I got traded to Baltimore. I played him
twice.
>> What' you see from him in particular in
the second time you played him for
Baltimore where he didn't have a great
first half. You guys got to him a little
bit and then he progressed and started
to make plays and responded to what you
guys be able to get pressure on him and
he felt and I think a lot of people
around it felt that was a huge growth
game for Drake.
>> I think I mean I think so. Uh he was
resilient. I mean, to be honest, from
what I remember, we were up like 14 in
the fourth quarter and
>> I had sacked him
>> and I I thought he was going to get in
his head, but you know,
>> he turned that thing around. He made a
critical throw on uh I think it was
fourth down
>> to Digs
>> to Yeah. to digs on the out route.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. And I remember like like Dan,
that's a hell of a throw cuz he just at
the window. Could have been picked off.
>> Yeah.
>> If our DB at the time uh was a little
bit faster, it was great coverage, too.
And uh that game really showed how he
doesn't get rattled in big in big
moments like that cuz that was a big
game.
>> What do you want Patriots fans to know
about you?
>> Um that I'm a tough, hardworking guy.
That's really what I want him to know.
>> What how do you describe yourself as a
football player? What are the best
qualities you think you bring to this
team? I
>> think my effort. I'm always uh even if
I'm I'm messing up, even if I'm wrong,
I'm I'm trying to make sure I do things
at 100 miles per hour and uh
leadership, too.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. So, hopefully hopefully that
translate to the field.
>> How do you describe this day? I mean,
you're not a rookie.
>> Yeah.
>> But it's a new environment, so it's kind
of a unique day, isn't it?
>> Yeah. It's always unique. Anytime you're
in the NFL and you get to be on the team
and you get to do things like this is
always unique. You can't take these
things for granted.
>> Have you met uh any of the veterans yet?
You met Drake May. He's here today,
right? not in meet him. Uh I spoke with
uh Herold a little bit just quick
because I'm I'm doing a bunch of stuff
around the facility getting acclimated
and I was able to meet uh Hunter Henry
about to have a baby. So uh congrats to
him for that. But I haven't met I
haven't got a chance to meet guys who
are already here really.
>> And your relationship with Mike Greyel.
Just talk about heed you at Ohio State
didn't come back.
>> Yeah. Yeah. He was part of that
recruitment when I was first like coming
into the scene and then he end up being
gone. So that connection kind of went
away. But yeah, I know he has a he has a
great Buckeye lineage and that's
something I appreciate because you know
I'm a Buckeye so I know how he gets
down. I know where how his mindset is.
He
>> we know all we know all about we
>> Yeah, that pipeline's real.
>> Is he the same guy now that you met
years ago?
>> Yeah, it seems like it.
>> How so? Well, describe him your
relationship.
>> Um I don't have a I I can't say I have a
much of a relationship with him because
I haven't got a chance to be really
really under him. But just just today
meeting with him, down to earth, easy to
talk to. probably one of the most
easiest talk to head coaches I've been
around. Somebody that gets it because he
played and he's he's uh he's coached it
at a high level. He's won so he knows
what to do and that's something I
appreciate.
>> I apologize if you've been asked about
this, but your free agency process, how
did that go? Was obviously New England
won out, but were there other teams that
were sort of interested in you and how
were those conversations?
>> Yeah, there was a bunch of teams
interested. Um the the conversations
were real, man. It was it was a tough
decision, but you know, I guess the edge
was always New England and um I'm glad
it worked out. It was it was a tough
process. My agent handled most of the
the nuances of what what goes on and I
was just doing my part, which was
working out and staying out the way and
waiting for a phone call.
>> Growing up, what were your memories of
New England and and sort of what does
this sort of environment mean now that
you're here? All I think I remember is
Tom Brady and winning and that was the
only thing I really remember. And uh
this environment here, I mean, I don't
know, but I played against here. The
crowd is great. Um it's been tough to
play here. It's been it's always been
tough to play against New England,
whether
even during the down years. So, I'm
excited to be a part of something
special like this. They just came off a
Super Bowl. Hopefully, I can be a part
of a team that's a part of a Super Bowl.
I've never been in the playoffs before,
so hopefully it works out. I sorry if
this was asked before, but I wonder like
when you've learned that it would be the
Patriots or that the Patriots was an
option.
>> How cool is it? Like they just made the
Super Bowl. You're joining a team that
has winning expectations. What does that
mean for your career?
>> Means a lot. I mean, I get a chance to
to build some legacy. They just came out
of the Super Bowl. Like I just said
previously, I've never been to the
playoffs and being part of I've never
joined the team who just won the well,
not one, but who just went to the Super
Bowl. So, I'm excited, you know, to be a
part of that. I know they got a bunch of
their guys that are still here. So, they
they know what to do. And what do where
do you see your game fitting in in Zach
Wilk?
>> Um just being a big tough edge guy who
can who can set set an edge, play the
run well, and then then when it's time
to do pass rush, I'm a I'm a physical
rusher, so I'm going try to get my hands
on guys.
>> What do you want Patriots fans to know
about?
>> I'm tough, rugged, and I'm a family man.
>> Traymont, you're listed at 281.
>> Yeah.
>> Did you play at 281 last year?
>> No.
>> Yeah. More in the 260s? Yeah, I'm in the
60s. Yeah, 65.
>> And is that where they would like? I
mean, it's early yet. You don't know
yet?
>> I don't know.
>> I plan on being 65 when I play. So,
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> And family coming up to New England?
>> Uh, my fiance is she's here. My our uh
our two little babies are not here. And
I'm glad because they would be probably
doing some crazy [__] right now. So, uh
they're they're they're my everything
and u I'm happy when when they're here.
So, I can't wait for them to get here.
>> New England.
>> Thank you. Appreciate it.
>> Had a lot of success rushing from the
interior. Yeah.
>> Um, what allows you at 265 to be able to
do that efficiently?
>> My experience of doing it when I was
heavy and uh I was already like a the a
lighter dackle. So, losing what 30 lbs
and it doesn't feel any different. So,
I understand how to I understand how to
rush out of three tech and I understand
how to rush on edge
>> that you feel like that give you an
advantage having that sort of
>> I think so. I think so. I think I
definitely think so. How much did um
Mike Greyel his coaching style and
everything you know impacted him?
>> Um it impacted a lot of it. I can't give
you a percentage but like he it
definitely impacted um that pipeline
from Ohio State. You know that lineage
is real and uh I'm happy to be a part of
somebody who gets it and gets me.
>> There was some reporting that he was a
part of recruiting you to Ohio State. Is
that accurate?
>> Uh like way back then. I was like young
though. So yeah. So, what what do you
remember about meeting him back then?
>> I didn't really expect to meet him. I
was I was like on the phone
conversations and then he was gone. So,
uh I end up talking to another guy. His
name was Stan Drayton trying to recruit
me to continue it. But
>> so kind of just like started the
>> Yeah. Yeah. In and out. Him and like
Luke Fickle.
>> Were you aware last year
had interest in trading for you?
>> Um I did get wind of that. Uh I don't
know how true that is. Is it is it true?
Is it true?
>> It's true. Yeah, I know. I did I did
know they're interested. So, it's it's
kind of a cool moment that I'm here now.
>> Kind of full circle.
>> Hey, J. I'm Sophie. I'm sorry. I'm
probably going to ask some of the same
questions you've gotten asked. Uh so,
very much apologize. It's all right.
>> But, um New England, what was it about
here that stood out to you and made you
want to come here?
>> Um Braves and winning to be simple about
it. Uh they literally just got a Super
Bowl a month ago. Um, like I've been
saying, uh, I've never been in playoffs.
So hopefully now that I'm here, playoffs
and Super Bowl appearances will happen
again. And, um, and on top of that,
Graves, uh, somebody who's played the
position, uh, gets it and he's done, not
only did he play at a high level, but
he's coached at a high level. So,
>> what, how would you describe your game
personally?
>> Uh, rugged and tough. I I think that's
the best way to go about it.
>> And Ed was a big need coming into this.
um kind of
>> coming into the off season for the
Patriots. How can you kind of step up
and maybe help them, you know, because
even last year that was a big need.
>> Yeah, stepping up cuz I I I'm versatile
so I can do I can I can play inside and
out. Um I think I'm I'm a smart player
so I get it and uh I've had experience
playing at every position on on the
field on on the D line. So feel like I
can do it do it all.
>> How many of the other guys on the roster
did you know coming out? Uh,
two to three.
>> Anyone specific?
>> Um, no. Trayvon,
I know the Mumford and uh I feel like
somebody else I'm blinking on.
>> Somebody else.
>> Mike Brown in Tennessee, too.
>> Yeah, I played Mike. Yeah. Uh, I know
Moses. Competed against Moses a lot.
Uh, I'm trying to think who else.
>> I think that might be it.
>> What were your outside thoughts on this
defense watching them last year?
>> Um, that they're legit. I I was
impressed with them when we played
against them uh the couple times I did
from two different teams. So, uh I feel
like if they were consistent, then they
should be consistent now. It's a really
good defense.
>> What were what have conversations with
Zack Core been like? Um because he's
someone who um was the acting defensive
coordinator last year, but it's now kind
of like the in that official role. What
have what has that been like? And um
because obviously I know Braves was
probably your, you know, the pull kind
of here, but what has it been like to
get to know him a little bit? No,
>> it's been great. Um, you know, it's been
quick, but sooner rather than later, I'm
going to get to know him more and I can
give you a better answer. Then,
>> how much do you pride yourself just in
your versatility just in being able to
go inside outside?
>> Uh, I pride myself in that a lot. You
know, once that that versatility, that
versatility label got that got stuck on
me, I wanted to keep it. So, uh, I I I
just want to be able to to rush the
passure well at at three tech or at one
tech or zero if I have to and nine
technique. So, I pride myself and I work
it all the time and my training habits
so I can do it.
>> What led you to drop the 281 to the T6?
>> Uh, you know, my career I started off in
a DTackle and um, you know, I started
transitioning into being an outside
linebacker, which just kind of just it
kind of just happened and I I knew to be
successful I need to cut some weight.
>> So nice to meet you.
>> Thank you. Nice to meet you.
>> Thank you. Appreciate you.
>> Oh, thank you. Sorry.
I really enjoy watching it. Well, so I
know you're listed at like 280. Oh, you
were in like 260s range. You can try to
stand up outside linebacker.
>> Yeah, I'm I'm an assistant. I don't need
>> Can you tell me a little bit about your
transition from defensive tackle to now
all the way going to outside linebacker?
I know you still kick inside, but like
what's that been like? It's a very
unique career.
>> It's hard, man. Like it's a I don't it's
not too many people or guys I don't
>> I've heard go from Dackle to outside
linebacker. And you know, it was a it
was definitely like a some some fear
into that because I'm in a whole
different realm. I'm rushing in a
different area when I first started off.
>> And uh once I got playing, I end up
getting better than I played. And I knew
like, all right,
>> I got to find some way to to to elevate
more because, you know, coaches, they're
doing their jobs. They're not going to
tell you what you need to do always. So,
I had to figure out what I need to do.
And I knew cutting some weight helped me
grow my game.
>> Last year, it showed a lot. Mhm. And
from a physical perspective, obviously
it's very different being in the
trenches, but from a vision standpoint.
>> Yeah.
>> What is it like and how do you adapt
from going inside where there's all this
stuff going around and you kind of have
one objective to being that standup guy
where there's a little bit more on a
clip.
>> Yeah. No, you go from literally go from
saying nothing to everything just like
that. And it it threw me off. I I used
to make a joke about how the edges have
it so easy
>> and now like n the tackles have way
easier. Trust me, I've I've seen both
areas. So, uh
>> it's it was a hell of a transition, man.
But I think I'm doing a good job. But I
know you reached careerh high in sacks
last year. I don't know if you follow
all the advanced stuff, but pressures as
well. Um, was there anything specific
that you felt like went into that? Is it
opportunity? Was there something in your
game that you felt took a step forward?
>> Opportunity. Um, along with sometimes,
you know, just I like to say like a
basketball like just hit my shots. You
know, I worked so much and uh
so much uh so much time just doing it.
I'm able to just to be smarter about
what I do and I'm able to read alignment
a little better than what I used to. So,
I think that helped a lot.
>> Also, think of that. You can win in a
lot of different ways. You got the spin
moves, long arm, and everything. How
would you describe your play style and
what makes you such a great fit in this
Patriots defensive system?
>> I think I'm breaking it tough. I think I
bring a lot of aspects, whether it's
some some finesse, some power. Um, and I
think that uh my versatility has carried
me a long way within this league, and I
want to kind of keep that that that
label on me being versatile so I can uh
hopefully extend my career into my
mid-30s.
>> Absolutely.
>> I love ball. I want to play as much as
long as possible. So, um, I'm going just
do it the right way so I can talk to you
guys.
>> And were you familiar with Harold Langry
or any of the guys in the ed room or is
this just me the whole
>> Yeah, I was familiar with them. Uh, just
because guys would jokingly say back
when I first signed with Tennessee cuz I
knew I knew a lot more guys in they
would jokingly say me and Harold like
they were always calling me big Harold.
>> Really?
>> Yeah. So,
>> that motivates you to get all the sacks
like no.
>> No, no, no. I'm still I'm still me. I'm
still Dre at the end of the day. But I
got familiar with Harold just because of
the guys talked about him so much to me
and Mike I play with Mike Mike Mike Ron
told he used to say too
>> really.
>> Yeah. So it's it's it's funny now I have
teammates. I got to get chance to really
talk to him but I'm sure when we do I I
I'll realize what everybody's talking
about.
>> Right. Right.
>> Awesome. Thank you so much for your
time. Congratulations. Great to meet
you.
>> Good. How are you?
>> I'm Bob the playbyplay for the Pats.
>> Okay. Cool. Nice to meet you.
>> Nice to meet you. Welcome to New
England.
>> Thank you. as as a home team player now.
>> Yeah,
>> we certainly see you a lot last few
years.
>> Yes.
>> I guess to start, can you tell me about
the decision to sign here? What
influenced you?
>> Uh, so the main thing being, you know, a
good young team, played against this
team multiple years, but uh, in the last
couple years, I've I've really liked
what I've seen from, you know, these
these these new players they've gotten.
So, with Drake May, obviously young
quarterback, but, you know, he's playing
with the best of them.
>> What stands out about the play style in
the game?
>> It's physical, and that's my style of
game. Uh, and I know Vrael preaches that
and, you know, bringing the physicality
and the tenacity to a team and letting
that be the identity of the team really.
>> And Josh McDaniel's offense
traditionally has had a pretty prominent
role. Yeah.
>> So, yeah. So, so I talked to Josh and
obviously with James Develin here for a
long time. I've made pretty good friends
with him over the years because, you
know, he works with the PA now. Uh, so
yeah, I'm excited to see what I can do
in this offense.
>> Um, you said you've talked to James
Develin obviously extensive history. How
much did Josh maybe I don't know if
you've talked with Josh yet, but if you
have um how much has he talked to you
about the history of the fullback world
in this office?
>> So, yeah, that was one of the first
things he said to me. Obviously, uh he
said that, you know, he's had a history
with fullbacks and he loves a, you know,
a true, you know, vicious style player
and the physicality has been being
preached ever since I walked in this
building. So, I'm excited for it.
>> Is vicious a word you use to describe
your play style?
>> Oh, yeah. Absolutely. Tenacious.
>> Tenacious.
>> Sorry. What are your uh just I don't
know how much you look at like other
offenses and stuff, but what are your
initial impressions just watching
Roandre Stevenson and Trey Young.
>> Uh so honestly Raandre Stevenson reminds
me a lot of myself. He's also a
physical, you know, bigger guy that you
know will lower his pads, not afraid of
contact, you know, hunts the contact
instead of being the one hunting.
>> Obviously being in Buffalo, what has
been your sort of overall expectations
of New impressions of New England over
the last six years? You know, how has
that sort of changed? Uh, so being in
Buffalo, we didn't really like New
England too much, but uh, you know, I
don't have any bad blood towards anybody
for any rivalries or any team for that
matter. I'm just excited to be here and
super grateful for the opportunity.
>> How have you seen that sort of the
franchise change over coaching changes?
>> Yeah, absolutely. So, so when I first
got in the league, obviously, you know,
New England Ram, the AFC East. Um, and
then we won it five or six years
straight. I don't know what it was
exactly, but it was it was cool to see
um you know how it could all come
together and how they bounced back and
you know they you know had a couple off
years if you want to call it um but now
they're they're a very prominent young
team.
>> I'm curious I can't remember you played
for Brian when he was they do you see
overlap between what you guys did there
with him and what you expected
>> Yeah. Actually, I was just meeting with
Thomas Brown, the tight end's coach, and
he gave me the playbook, and I'm like,
"Yeah, I know a lot of these words." So,
I'm hoping that the uh the transition to
a new offense or somewhat new would be
smooth.
>> Uh I know you played a significant
special teams role as well in Buffalo.
Did you talk to Jeremy Springer at all
during the process?
>> Yeah, actually, we were just sitting
down eating lunch together. Um yeah, he
asked me a lot about um you know, my
last few coordinators and my role and he
told me about a couple plays. He's like,
"Dang, he got us again." So, I'm happy
to be on this side of it um and work
with him. He seems like a really great
guy.
>> What are your recollections from the
week five game when New England came to
Buffalo? It seemed like sort of a
breakout
>> for New England.
>> Yeah, that that was a that was a
statement game for them. Steph had a
great game and really the entire offense
was rolling. Um and I was like, "Wow,
this this team is is legit. It's not
just, you know, a one hit wonder. This
is this team's here to stay."
>> You talk about the the culture here that
they've built, the the identity,
physicality, the viciousness. Is that
consistent with what you experienced in
Buffalo, particularly as you guys got it
going? Yeah. Um I don't know if in
Buffalo it was ever uh the physicality
was ever preached. Um not like Verbel
preaches it at least. But for me that
like that's how I pride myself. Like
that's the the key to my game. Like I
want you to turn on the tape and be like
that guy just jumping off the tape. Look
at his effort, his energy, his
physicality. Like I want the linebackers
to know and anybody really DBs, anybody
knows like when you meet me like it's
going to be a collision.
>> How do you hone that? Obviously like
restrictions on how much you can hit in
practice and all that. Is that just
instinct? Is that something you can work
on? Is that something that has to come
in the game?
>> Yeah, a little bit of all of it. Um,
yeah, you can work on it, but obviously
you can't do too much because you don't
want to, you know, keep piling those
hits on your body. But, uh, a lot of it
is instinct when it comes to the game
time. It's just like that guy in front
of me is not making the tackle. And
that's just what I pride myself on.
Every time I step on the field, like my
responsibility is not going to be near
the ball.
>> Have you had conversations with Matt
Collins?
>> Yeah. Uh, so, uh, I actually reached out
to him uh, just two days ago uh, and he
told me I was going to love it here.
told me all great things about it and um
how Brabble really takes care of his
guys.
>> How strongly did you consider other
teams Patriots? Were they really number
one from the outside?
>> Yeah, there was there was a couple
rumors um early on in the free agency
process. Uh but I was just like, you
know, Vable reached out to me uh and was
like, you know, we want we want you
here. And I was like, that's that's the
type of guy that that's I want somebody
that wants me, you know, I want to go
somewhere where I'm valued.
>> You said you talked to Matt Collins.
Were there any other guys that reached
out kind of right after you signed? Who
else have you heard from on the team?
>> Um, oh, I talked to Brendan Schooler.
Um, we've we've talked a lot over the
last few years, you know, being special
teams guys and we really respect each
other's game and, uh, he hit me up when
I signed and he was super thrilled. I
tried to get 41 off of him, but he
wouldn't let it go.
>> Any ideas for money?
>> No. He's just like, I can't let it go,
man. I'm like, all right, fine.
>> Any ideas what what you want if you
can't get 41?
>> So, I wanted 21, but uh, KB beat me to
it. So, uh, so 44 is going to be what
I'm rolling with.
>> Traditional fullback number.
>> How do you describe this day? You're not
a rookie, but you're coming to a new
place.
>> Yeah, it's a it's rookie year part two.
I feel like I'm doing this. I mean, I
never got to do all of this uh cuz I
came in when it was co. So, um my first
day in an NFL um building was training
camp practice one. So, that was that was
a little crazy, but uh this is really
cool. It does feel like I'm, you know,
starting over from scratch, but at least
I have some knowledge of what to expect
at this time.
>> Two quick things. What do you want
Patriots fans to know about you?
>> Uh you're going to give my all every
time I step on the field. You'll never
have to question that. What do you think
your can you describe yourself as a
football player? What do you think the
best qualities you bring to a football?
>> Um, so like I said to these guys that
tenac tenacity and being tenacious, you
know, in everything I do is is what I
would pride myself on, what I would
describe myself as. When you go back to
like your original about this team and
and Drake quarterback, I mean, a lot of
comparisons for what they're worth for
him coming out of college and even last
year related his skill set
>> to Josh's. Yeah. Do do you see some
similarities there? And can you expound
on why Drake?
>> Yeah. So, so I just met Drake this
morning. Uh when I walked in, I I saw
him for the first time. I'm like, "Wow,
he's bigger than I expected. I did not
expect him to be that large." Um, but
yeah, he has a lot of the same qualities
as Josh and I know he was in the the
talks for MVP just like Josh was. So,
um, yeah, I believe in him a ton and I'm
excited to see what he can do.
>> Are you prepared for tush push?
>> Oh, yeah, absolutely. I don't know. I
don't know if the if the Patriots run
the tush push a lot, but I'm hoping we
can get that in.
>> Have you heard from Bill's fans since
>> Oh, yeah. My phone is still buzzing. Uh,
yeah. A lot of a lot of fans are
heartbroken and feel, you know, betrayed
and call me a traitor or whatever. I'm
just like, it's not it wasn't my fault.
>> It's just business, right?
>> It's just business. No hard feelings
towards the Bills. Um I love everybody
in that building still, but you know,
sometimes it's it's good for a fresh
start.
>> What was your impression? Sorry. What
was your impression of this Patriots
team?
>> Uh so I was actually telling somebody
earlier uh the second game we played, I
don't remember what week it was. Um but
I remember standing in the middle of the
field. It was on kickoff return and uh
Travis Scott was up in the box and he
was doing his song or whatever and the
entire sideline dancing and jumping
around on each other. I was like, "Wow,
like they look like they have a lot of
fun playing together." playing in the
AFC East. Sorry. Your whole career.
>> Um, how did you feel about the Patriots
team? Elijah just said, "Yeah, I'm gonna
be real with you. We hated the
Patriots."
>> Yeah. So, yeah. So, like I was telling
these guys, yeah, we weren't too fond of
the Patriots. Um, and and I got into I
got to the Bills, you know, after Brady
was gone from here. So, I didn't really
experience the the hatred for Tom Brady
that everybody in Buffalo has. Uh, I I
like Tom Brady growing up. I like I
acknowledge him as a goat. Everybody
else everybody else I know a
acknowledges him as such and rightfully
so. There's a statue out there of him.
Um, but uh, yeah, they didn't we didn't
really care too much for the Patriots,
but Raider know.
>> Yeah, I don't have any hard feelings
towards the Patriots.
>> You play such a unique position. When
did you become a fullback?
>> Uh, so in 2016 I got to Toledo and
Kareem Hunt was a starting running back
and I was like, there's no way I'm
getting on the field.
>> I was I was a running back my whole
life. Um, and then when I got uh to camp
or got to Toledo and we went to camp,
uh, Jason Kandle, my head coach, said,
you know, we can only take so many guys
to camp. There was like a roster limit
back then. I don't know if it still
exists, but uh I was like, I need to go
to camp. Like I walked on. So I was
like, if I don't show up in camp, how am
I ever going to make this team? Um so I
switched to fullback and here we are.
>> Just to put on weight.
>> No, I was actually I was a 240lb running
back. So I was already a fullback
playing running back essentially.
>> What did you did you know much about
like the position of fullback or like
what switching?
>> So growing up my favorite running back
to watch was Leenius Tomlinson and his
fullback was Lorenzo O'Neal. Um, so I
always knew about the fullback and I
essentially just think of the fullback
as the running back without the ball.
Uh, I think of him as the bus driver
really like so the ball is following the
running or the following the fullback.
So it's the same type of like reading
the schemes whatever like if the running
back would cut off this guy, you got to
cut off him to make your block.
>> And I also want to I apologize as Josh
McDaniels is known as an offensive
coordinator who loves a good fullback,
loves to have a fullback. Um, what do
you know about him and what's your level
of excitement to get to, you know,
>> Yeah. So, I've talked to Josh McDaniels
and obviously being a football fan my
whole life, I've I've seen a lot of
Patriot success. So, so watching uh
James Develin, I've actually become
pretty good friends with him. Uh he was
an NFLPA uh guy for us in Buffalo. So,
I' I've learned a lot about the fullback
just watching over the years watching my
favorite running backs.
>> Important question. Do you wear a neck
roll?
>> I do not.
>> Has that ever been a consideration?
>> No, I think it's a little too bulky for
my liking. You
>> mentioned Lorenzo Neil Delin. Do you
have like a top five fullbacks all time?
Uh, so actually we just started a group
chat. All the fullbacks.
>> Okay.
>> Uh, all the current fullbacks, all the
past fullbacks, we're all in a group
chat together. But, uh,
>> so
>> I don't want to get you in trouble in
the group chat.
>> I don't want to get in trouble in the
group chat either, but I feel like I got
to put Mike at one, but I got to put a
little astric next to it because he was
really a running back. They gave him the
ball way more than any other fullback.
But then I would put, you know, Jim
Brown's got to be up there, too. But
that's another one that's more of a
running back than a fullback. But like
true fullbacks, I'd have to put Lorenzo
Neil as my as as my number one. He was
my favorite watching up or watching
growing up and still think that stands
true.
>> Big role in one of the most infamous
plays in Buffalo Bills history.
>> Exactly. So yeah, I didn't know I was
going to be a Bill growing up watching
him, but uh yeah, Lorenzo Neil's that
guy.
>> How many fullbacks are in that chat?
>> Uh like 30 of us.
>> Really?
>> Yeah.
>> That's awesome.
>> For those who don't know you, how would
you describe?
>> Tenacious. That's that's that's the word
of the day. Physical. Once you turn on
the tape and and you're going to see,
you know, you see somebody's head pop,
it's going to be because of me. What are
your thoughts running back?
>> Yeah, I'm I'm really excited to work
with those guys. Um I was just telling
them that uh Raandre is basically a
fullback within himself. You know, he
doesn't really need a fullback. He's his
own guy. You know, he brings his pads
and, you know, Trayvon's a speedster and
I'm excited to, you know, make that one
block and have feel him cut off my hip
and it's off to the races. Does
>> it feel surreal to be here this morning
and coming in everything New England,
everything just coming from Buffalo?
>> Yeah, it it's uh it still doesn't feel
real. Like I woke up in my hotel room
this morning that also I didn't even
know all this was on the other side
coming from this side. Um I thought this
was just in the middle of a neighborhood
in the middle of nowhere. I had no idea
this was over here. Uh anyway, I stayed
in the hotel uh right across the street
over here and uh open my uh curtains
this morning and I see Gillette Stadium
and I'm just like wow this is real. It's
here.
>> Are you looking forward to the ride into
Buffalo Stadium and having the fans
going crazy yelling out?
>> I don't know. I don't know. I don't know
how too f how fond of me they are right
now but I'm hoping not to get too much
hate from them when I go back. How
comfortable are you in pass protection
and what would you mean that you know
help protect?
>> Yeah. Yeah. Um I'm actually really
comfortable in pass protection. I've
never done it from like the running back
standpoint and I'm looking forward to
doing some of that but as a tight end
fullback. I've done a lot of pass pro
and I I feel really comfortable in it.
>> Seems like going from Josh Allen to
>> I feel like it's going to be a lot of
the same style. Um I know Josh is kind
of like a improviser and kind of does
his own thing, but I've seen that in
Josh's game too or Drake's game too.
>> A lot of people do talk about the
comparison. Um, do you find it kind of
like ironic or funny in a way that you
went from like an office with Josh Allen
and then like his biggest comp in the
NFL currently is Drake?
>> Yeah, and that's what I was just telling
these guys earlier when I walked in and
met Drake this morning. I did not expect
him to be that large. He's he's built
just like Josh.
>> What um what was it like meeting Drake?
>> Yeah, he's a cool guy. Uh he's starting
to get a little beard now. So,
>> yeah, maybe I wasn't supposed to say
that.
>> Little sneak peek
to grow with him.
>> Yeah, I'm excited. A young player. Um
cuz obviously when I got to Buffalo,
Josh was uh three years in not fully
established, but he was already like we
knew he was going to be the guy. And you
know, Drake is obviously the guy here,
but I'm excited to be with a young
quarterback and help him grow in his
progression as well.
>> How much do you fit in Mike Rabel's
philosophy? Like he likes violence and
you talk about tenacious and everything.
How much do you like violence as well as
being tenacious?
>> Yeah, I love that. And then that's what
he's been preaching to me since I walked
in the door here is like like we love
your style of play and we love what you
bring physicalitywise. And I talked to
Thomas Brown, the tight end coach, and
he echoed the same thing uh with Julian
Hill. And I
>> Sounds like the fans aren't going to
like you.
>> We'll see.
>> Love you. You know what I mean? You seem
like a football player through and
through.
>> Through and through. Yeah, I love the
contact. I've always been like that
since I was a kid. I mean, I remember
playing in the backyard with my friends
and we would play full tackle street,
you know, all the way through. No pads,
nothing. We're lowering our shoulder on
each other. What were those
conversations with Mike Fragel like to
to be able to get like you know a feel
for what he's kind of established here?
>> Yeah, he's he's a real u players coach
and I I felt that from him in the
conversations that we've had. He said he
he takes really good care of the guys
and the the one thing that he really
instilled in me he was saying that you
know you get in what you put out or you
get out what you put in and he said like
you treat us right we'll treat you right
and I'm really looking forward to that.
>> You referenced your conversation with
Jeremy talking about Brendan contact
>> talk to who? Jeremy
>> Jeremy Springer. Oh yes.
>> Special teams and the role that it's
played in your career and your longevity
in the NFL.
>> Yeah. So that's really how I've uh made
it this far. U getting on the field. My
first couple years I didn't really play
a lot of offense. It was all special
teams and you know everybody preaches
you know that's how you make your money.
That's how you keep a job. That's how
you get a helmet on Sunday because you
know you can only dress was it 49 48
guys. So it's like you got to be a
fourcourt guy if you want to make sure
you have a helmet every Sunday. So
special teams has always been huge for
me. I played it in high school, college,
and and and now in the NFL. And even in
college when I was a a a bonafide
starter on the offense, I was still on
every face. So, it's always been a huge
part of my game.
>> What was your first impression of Jeremy
Springer? Because, you know, we've had,
you know, we do our interviews. He's a
high energy guy. Impression you
>> and and I really like that he values
he's already shown me that he values my
opinion. He's asking me what I've done,
what I'm comfortable in, you know, how
we did certain things in Buffalo to see,
you know, how I could grow in his
special team system. What do you know
about the the offense's identity, what
it wants to be? Yeah. In a perfect
world, what have you learned about that?
>> It's very it's very versatile. Uh like I
was saying, Thomas Brown, the tight end
coach, he told me how multiple uh
personnel groups we're going to have
and, you know, no, not one guy is
certain is set to one, you know, one
position. We're all going to be
interchangeable pieces. So, I'm looking
forward to that.
>> Just looking around at some of the other
guys that the team has added on offense
>> and between you and obviously Elijah and
Julian and even Romeo is supposedly a
very good runer.
>> Yeah. like how excited do you get
understanding that that will be a part
of it?
>> Yeah. So, I love to run the ball. Um not
just not not just when the ball's in my
hand, but just running the ball and
especially when the other team knows
we're running the ball cuz it's like
they can know what we're doing, but they
still got to stop it. And that's my
favorite thing when the linebackers are
coming downhill, DBs are coming and you
still make a great block and it's still
a great run. You know, there's nine guys
in the box and we're still averaging
four yards a pop. So, it's just it has
an attitude about it that I love to
carry. Is there is that becoming a more
important part of offensive football?
>> Yeah, I think it's coming back um from
from like 2020 to like 2023 everything
was air raid you know throw the ball 50
60 times a game and I think teams are
now realizing that you know without a
good run game that doesn't work very
long.
>> How do you uh
>> make amends with the Buffalo people? you
were obviously very you're very
important to them and there were a lot
of people that were upset about it
especially now you're upset because
>> you're with the rival.
>> Yeah. So, like I said, uh my phone is
still buzzing. Uh people are heartbroken
about it. Uh but I still have a ton of
love for them and I hope that they feel
the same for me.
>> Do you mind a few more?
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. If I may um talk about being back
for the kickoff return here this season
>> for you, what's the difference the last
few years? that rule changed in your
role
about it.
>> Yeah, so the kickoff rule has changed a
lot u in the special in the kickoff game
obviously. Uh so I used to be a wedge
guy. I don't know if you guys even know
what the wedge is,
but uh yeah, so the the the back two or
three guys would, you know, run up and
kick out whoever, you know, double
triple team, but now there's no more
wedge. There's not even a you know, the
off returner is just kind of back there
to, you know, help the returner. Uh but
now I'm p predominantly on the front
line and that's a whole different game
but I've adjusted well to it and um at
the end of last year I actually started
being the off returner. So that kind of
got me back in that wedge world and you
know being a lead blocker. It's right in
my wheelhouse. Um so it's kind of like a
inside zone play is how I used to tell u
Ray Davis my my returner how that we
would look at it. It's like okay I'm
going to if this guy does this I'm going
to kick him this way or if he goes this
way I'm going to log him that way. You
read off of me and make your cut and
it's off to the races. Seems like some
of the better teams have really created
a run play out of the kickoff now.
>> Yeah. Seattle will pay towards.
>> Yeah. That's the best way to do it
because you know if you can wall off one
side of the field because you know from
like the four over if we're running the
right return the L the L5 and on
irrelevant. So if you can get all those
guys to just slow down a few steps we're
off to the races.
>> How you doing?
>> Good. How are you?
>> I'm Evan. Nice to meet you.
>> Nice to meet you.
>> Uh I just wanted to ask you just you
know I feel like now fullbacks are not
just lining up in the back field and
just going forward you ton of
versatility in your game. Just what kind
of goes into that to be able to play on
the in on in motion the wing.
>> Yeah. So yeah, so growing up my whole
life I was a running back. Um and then
when I got to college I I was forced to
switch to fullback and that's really
where it started to be like okay you got
to know a little bit of everything
because I was like the fullback and
tight end. Yeah.
>> Um so I was used to being split out
wide. I was used to being in the eye or
offset however wherever it was. Like I
just knew that I had to get my job done
because I was a walk-on. I was like I
can't look bad out here. So like I'm
going to make sure that they know that I
I know what I'm doing every time I step
on the field.
>> Yeah. And the other thing just seemed
like you guys were really productive
last year with play action when you were
on the field. Just how important is it
for you to kind of sell that type of you
know look to the defense and
>> Yeah. So uh you know my coaches helped
me out a lot with that. Uh you know
being on the field for you know anytime
I was on the field it was like 80% of
the time I was on the field it was run
it was a run play. So, uh, it really
helped, you know, getting the the look
and getting, you know, the exotics to
stop on the defense and and really
making those linebackers bite because,
you know, if I was on the field, there's
a good chance it was going to be a run.
So, that helps out a lot.
>> Last one just seemed like you guys ran
that lineback play pretty consistently
with you out there. What about that
play, you know, did you like
>> So, that that is my favorite play still
to this day. Yeah, that is my favorite
play. Uh, yeah, we got the tight end
pulling out pulling over to kick out the
DN and the linebacker has to fit it. So
depending on how that DN fits, the
kickout block is where the linebacker is
going to fit. And a lot of times
>> the collision between the tight end and
DN, the linebacker couldn't find me. So
a lot of times I was wrapping around and
I had the edge on him because he
couldn't see me. So and and the way that
we timed it up with James' footsteps, it
was it was great because he was right.
All I had to do is get in his way and it
was see you later.
>> Yeah, I had the one against Carolina 64
to the house.
>> I'm sure you've been asked this before,
right? Elijah was just talking about
how, you know, you didn't necessarily
themselves playing for the Patriots,
playing for the Jets. What was your what
what did you think about the Patriots as
you were playing the Bills?
>> Um, so I never had any bad blood towards
him and I know I had to act like I did
and be all rah rah, we hate the
Patriots, blah blah blah, but I never
really got into that. I didn't have any
bad bad blood towards any team. Um, I
didn't get there in the whole Tom Brady
runs the runs the AFC era. So, it I I
never really had any bad blood towards
the Patriots.
>> You gave us your ranking on fullbacks.
And again, apologize for another special
teams question. Deacon Brendan, I would
imagine, is up in that class.
>> Oh, yeah. Yeah. And also, uh, Matt
Slater. I've met him multiple times.
He's a great guy, but, you know, he's
the pinnacle of special teams play, you
know, 20 whatever, uh, Pro Bowl nominees
or whatever. So, yeah, he's he's the
guy.
>> To jog your memory bank, what's it like
going against guys like
>> uh, yeah, schooler or like special?
>> Yeah. So on on the off day like on a
Tuesday like I'll take my time to go and
evaluate the other team special teams
unit and find the guys because a lot of
times that's where you can tell when the
returns going or if uh like on the on
the punt team like if that guy is
rushing like that's the block guy.
That's the guy that they want to block
the punt. So look for him to be doing
all types of loops and whatever up and
unders on the wing whatever. So like you
got you got to know every team has like
their special teams guy that they want
to make the plays and so it's always
good to be keen in on him and know
what's going on with him. What was your
journey to become a quarterback? I know
everyone's kind of
>> Yeah.
>> So, in 2016, I got to Toledo. Uh, Kareem
Hunt was the starting running back and I
was like, I'm never getting on the
field.
So, uh, so in in college, there was only
so many guys you can take to camp on
your roster. So, I talked to Jason
Campbell, the head coach there, and I
was like, hey, what do I got to do to
make it to camp? And he was like, "Well,
we can switch you to our fullback,
Hback, tight end role." And I was like,
"All right, I'm there." So, and the rest
is history.
>> Kind of interesting because the fullback
position kind of got phased out a little
bit around the league and
some of the other guys
used him. It seems like there is a
foothold now.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And I model my game after
use and Engled and and CJ Ham before he
retired. Um a lot of those guys, they do
things a lot the right way and they're
also very tenacious players and also
very versatile players and that's what I
like to be too. Like I don't want to be
just a guy that is, you know, running
his head into a wall. Like I can run
routes, I can, you know, I can block on
the perimeter. Whatever you need it to
be, like I'm your guy.
>> Oh yeah. I just you mentioned uh you
know your fullback rankings. I'll have
to get those from you later. But the uh
Josh McDaniels's history with the
fullback. How familiar were you with
that and how much did that play into
your
>> So like I was telling these guys um I I
know I'm good friends with James Develin
now. He's in the NFL PA so we've talked
a lot and he's had nothing but great
things to say about New England and
obviously growing up watching you know
the whole era of Patriots being the
greatest team ever. uh watching them
have a fullback and you know with Josh
McDaniels he knows how to use a fullback
and I'm excited to see what he does with
me.
>> Hey Rich
memory
Russell
>> Brady Russell
>> Russell for for Seattle guys.
>> Okay you faced him last year.
>> Yeah and they had they had another
fullback outs.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. I'm just curious other guys on the
league that stand out to you.
>> Yeah. There's a there's a lot of a lot
of up and cominging fullbacks like uh
Hunter uh I forget how I don't know how
to say his last name, but in in Dallas,
he's another young guy. I know he just
got his new contract and he's been
playing great and they use him more than
just a you know, run your head into a
wall guy. Like he gets the ball a good
amount. Um there's a and like you said,
the fullback position is starting to
come back.
>> Well, I'm sorry to get like deep into
the X's and nos. Go on your tape, but I
know there's one specific block you do
that I don't see a ton across talked
about it too.
>> Oh, you did? Well, okay. Well, I I did.
So, can you tell me a little bit more
about
>> Yeah. So that that actually is my
favorite play.
>> Okay.
>> Uh so like I was telling these guys, the
the tight end comes over, kicks out the
DN, and the linebacker has to fit off
how the DN plays the the kick out. So
you know, if it's a kick out, then the
linebacker has to fit inside. And if the
if the DN spills it, the linebacker has
to fit outside. And a lot of times the
collision between the tight end and DN,
the linebacker can't see me
>> because I'm coming from the other side.
So it's like a little bit of an element
of surprise for them. Even when they
know it's coming, they still have to be
instinctually like, okay, how am I going
to fit this? And by the time they figure
it out, I'm already on them. So, and the
vision on those kinds of plays and like
working with your tight end, what's that
process like and how do you get to the
point when to change a picture?
>> Yeah. So, it's just being having the
spacing to have to let that collision
happen to know which way I can react.
So, I'm sure if you've seen on tape,
there's been times where I insert or
there's been times where I've been
looping around is having that space off
the tight end to be able to fit it
correctly and then knowing if I need to
seal the backer in or kick him out.
>> So, and it just it all depends on how he
plays it and if he plays it wrong, it's
off to the races.
>> Yeah.
>> Great. Thank you.